Mike Thomas Product Design Lead

14+ years experience blending **Product Design, Visual Design and front-end** to help start-ups and scale-ups level-up and move faster. Proven experience in 0-1 initiatives, mentoring + coaching, hiring, design systems, accessibility and solving gnarly problems all while bringing positivity and good vibes.

+44 (0) 7891 850 097 <u>mikerst@gmail.com</u> <u>mikethomas.design</u> <u>in/mikerst</u>



EXPERIENCE



4.5 yrs | B2B SaaS ClimateTech | Feb 2020-Jun 2024 | Seed to Series A

Product Designer + Lead Product Designer

- Lead design for zero-to-one initiatives.
- Established processes for hitting AA accessibility across our flagship app.
- Established foundational design system including UI library and docs.
- Designed many tactical enhancements + new features.
- Helped grow design function from 2 to 7.
- Introduced regular habits to improve design team maturity.
- Helped standardise product thinking across the business via facilitation and documentation.
- Mentored colleagues from across the business, from design through to commercial and customer support.
- Designed and built company website, including onboarding colleagues to new CMS.



TotallyMoney 6 yrs | B2C FinTech | Mar 2013-Apr 2019 | Seed to Series B

Designer + Senior Designer + Product Designer

- Designed new and enhanced existing customer touch-points across web, mobile and key programmatic marketing channels.
- Designed and built a framework to make it easier to generate high-conversation-rate HTML email templates for various CRM programmes.
- I later switched to a Product-focussed role, where I helped to launch a 0-1 product that raced to over 1 million customers in under 12 months across web and native mobile.



ZEAL Network SE 4 mos | B2B CSR initiative | Mar 2009-Jun 2013

Digital Designer (Contract)

 Designed, wrote content for, and developed a custom Wordpress site for a corporate social responsibility initiative.



Metaphors 4 yrs | Design Agency | Jan 2009-Mar 2013

Digital Designer

Generalist digital design role, working directly with clients in B2B, B2E sectors on over 50 web projects, including brand work, pitching, HTML/CSS, and training clients on Metaphors' in-house CMS.

EDUCATION

University of Plymouth | 2007–2008

MSc Digital Art & Technology

Arts University College Bournemouth | 2002–2005

BA (Hons) Graphic Design

PERSONAL STACK

Reading UI + Prototyping

Range, UX Strategy Figma

Listening to Collaboration

Decoder, UX Podcast Miro

Playing Efficiency
Lies of P ChatGPT

Watching Organisation

Chasing Front-end

Half-marathon p.b. HTML, CSS, JS, Vue, 11ty,

Netlify

Obsidian and Notion

FEEDBACK

For All Mankind

"Mike's blend of leadership, design expertise, and genuine care for his colleagues made a lasting impact on both the team and the products we created."

Hua Zhang, Lead Service Designer

"Mike is an absolute pleasure to work with and would be an asset to any company. His expertise... from research, to UX and UI was extremely valuable to have within our team."

Pat Potestas, Senior Product Manager

"Just wanted to re-iterate that I'm incredibly grateful for everything you've done for me. I couldn't have wished for a better line manager."

Dom Hart, Senior Brand Designer